Guillermo Romero (310)619 – 4017

Romero61@ucsb.edu

Guillermo Romero (romero61.github.io)

VALUE PROPOSITION

Professional with 10+ years of proven experience in Logistics, Warehouse, operations, and supply chain management. Supply chain knowledge from end to end, able to diagnose, plan, integrate and optimize the supply chain. Ability to define and implement suppliers' strategies, demand planning, inventory management, logistics, warehousing, distribution, service policy. Continually focused on developing and implementing process controls and quality improvement initiatives that reduce costs and increase company revenue. Possesses excellent computer skills and the knowledge of how to implement appropriate systems.

EDUCATION

2023 - Pending

University of California, Santa Barbara -

Bren School Of Environmental Science & Management

Master of Environmental Data Science

2022

University of California, Santa Barbara

Bachelor of Science in Earth Science - Geohydrology Emphasis

Bachelor of Science in Geography - Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Emphasis

2020

El Camino Community College

Associate of Science in Physics for Transfer

Associate of Science in Mathematics for Transfer

Associate of Science in General Science - Honors

Associate of Arts in General Arts - Honors

Associate of Arts in General Studies Biology and Physical Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2018 – 2021 Best Buy

Los Angeles, CA

General Warehouse Worker

- o Ensures daily home deliveries for all Southern California locations are correctly loaded. Safeguards that defective and returned products are accurately processed and prepped for relocation. Routes orders by locating the specified product and moving it to the loading dock.
 - Packs smaller products into larger containers for shipments to our stores.
 - Loads merchandise onto trucks for shipment to company locations.
 - Confirms all work areas are clean and safe for the entire team by removing empty pallets, sweeping, cleaning up boxes and removing other debris.
 - Pull product according to order.

2017 - 2018

Tie 4 Safe

Paramount, CA

General Warehouse

- Responsible for the loading, unloading, and setup of equipment daily while following all truck safety
 procedures. Contributed to the development of new processes that reduced shipping time by two days and
 improved customer satisfaction.
 - Achieved exceptional levels of customer satisfaction through timely, accurate processing and shipping of orders.
 - Commended for team-oriented attitude, contributing to improved efficiency and nearly 100% accuracy in order tracking and processing.
 - Safely perform all job duties by adhering to driving regulations, road signs, and company safety policies and procedures.
 - Conduct material handling equipment inspections.

2016 - 2017

Qual-Pro

Gardena, CA

Inventory Material Expediter

- Transacted the shipping and receiving and movement of materials by using various computer functions and by following shipping and receiving procedures.
 - Received materials to include dock receipts, truck unloading, material handling and processing of receiving paperwork.
 - Ensures security and accountability of inventory through transaction documentation, process and procedure verification, and system review.

Guillermo Romero (310)619 – 4017

Romero61@ucsb.edu

Guillermo Romero (romero61.github.io)

- Responsible for preparing orders, pulling materials, packing boxes, placing orders in delivery area.
- Prepared product for shipment to include packaging for safe shipping, plus labeling and marking.

2010 – 2015 Best Buy Los Angeles, CA

SWAT Inventory Specialist

- Responsible for counting assigned product counts, entering counts into RSS, researching variances, and reporting discrepancies to management. Oversaw and prepared for annual physical inventory and assisted in post physical inventory reconciliation.
 - Supported senior management by delivering reports outlining performance to drive process improvements.
 - Coached employees around shrink trends and behaviors by communicating and coaching store
 employees and leadership on the importance of inventory integrity and any identified process gaps.
 - Conducted various Operations Department duties, not limited to: down stocking, shipping, receiving, supply ordering, merchandising, and completing OMS product requests.

Inventory Product Flow Specialist

- Primary duties included down stocking, merchandising to company product protection standards, completing daily and weekly sign batches, and completing assigned weekly planograms.
 - Minimized process discrepancies by spearheading drop-shipments and inventory.
 - Helped drive a positive customer experience by building relationships, exhibiting empathy, and providing solutions for their needs.
 - Completed daily replenishment to ensure the product was fully stocked on the sales floor.
 - Prepared PRC for shipment, shuttle preparation, shipping, receiving, completing OMS product requests, and completing appropriate research for inter-store transfers and requests.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- University of California, Santa Barbara Scholarship
- El Camino College Foundation Scholarship
- Recording Connection Recording Engineer Certificate
- OSHA Forklift Certification

KEY COMPETENCIES/SKILLS

- Leadership & Management
- Bilingual Spanish
- Computer Programs: MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint
- Coding Languages: Matlab, Python, R, SQL
- Mapping Programs: ArcPro, Qgis
- Confident Public Speaker
- Relationship and Team Building
- Customer Service Oriented
- Loss Prevention
- Strong Computer Skills
- Critical thinking proficiency
- Personal and Professional Integrity